<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Higgs0x Brain Dump</title>
    <link>http://redsec.blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Higgs0x Brain Dump</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://redsec.blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DPAPI Online/Offline Decryption</title>
      <link>http://redsec.blog/posts/2022/02/dpapi-online/offline-decryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redsec.blog/posts/2022/02/dpapi-online/offline-decryption/</guid>
      <description>Introduction DPAPI stands for Data Protection API and was introducted by microsoft in Windows 2000 and since then it is used heavily by windows even if you aren&amp;rsquo;t aware of it. Simply put, DPAPI lets you encrypt/decrypt data. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about encryption keys at all.
DPAPI has 2 simple API:
CryptProtectData()CryptUnprotectData()As you might already guessed it:
For encryption you use CryptProtectData()
For decryption you use CryptUnprotectData()</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRTP Certification/Training course Review</title>
      <link>http://redsec.blog/posts/2021/10/crtp-certification/training-course-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redsec.blog/posts/2021/10/crtp-certification/training-course-review/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Before starting HackTheBox Offshore I needed some background on attacking Active Directory environment. I had had some sysadmin experience in AD and it was time to going through penetration testing course focused on Active Directory. I had already heard about PentesterAcademy training course (Attacking and Defending Active Directory) and didn&amp;rsquo;t spend time on searching much back then and immediately purchased this course which is accompanying training course for CRTP examination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://redsec.blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redsec.blog/about/</guid>
      <description>Blog on my red teaming journey. My Main objective is learning complex topics through teaching others, that forces me to dig deep and don&amp;rsquo;t just execute &amp;ldquo;hackish&amp;rdquo; commands without understanding deeper meaning.
Blog posts will be about  Attack and Secure Active Directory environment Web Application Security Red Team tradecraft exploit development Explaining newly discovered 0days  Contact me  Email: ltakashvili[at]protonmail.com or goebbelsx[at]gmail.com Twitter: @Higgs0x  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backdooring using AdminSDHolder</title>
      <link>http://redsec.blog/posts/2021/09/backdooring-using-adminsdholder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redsec.blog/posts/2021/09/backdooring-using-adminsdholder/</guid>
      <description>In a red team operation when we gain Domain Admin privileges, we want to make sure we will have access to the environment even though system administrators or blue teamers notice it. In Active Directory environment amount of TTPs (Techniques, Tactics, Procedures) for persistence is huge. One common way to persist is to use AdminSDHolder container, which is in System container
Every 60 minutes SDPropagator in AD, will overwrite Protected groups ACL with AdminSDHolder ACL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTB Offshore Review</title>
      <link>http://redsec.blog/posts/2021/09/htb-offshore-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://redsec.blog/posts/2021/09/htb-offshore-review/</guid>
      <description>Introduction At the beginning, HackTheBox was platform known for just a single box exercises but it evolved a lot and become one of the best platform for honing your cyber security skills and tradecraft.
One of the best feature of this platform is its prolabs
 Dante Offshore RastaLabs Cybernetics APTLabs  Prolabs are huge labs composed of several domains and forests, spanned across different subnets and each one of them varies by difficulty and sizes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
